Akshay Rajkumar

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India



akshayrajkumar96@gmail.com



+917708031516



linkedin.com/in/akshay-rajkumar

Summary

I am a SAP ABAP Senior Consultant with over 6 years of experience in ABAP and ABAP on HANA. My work is primarily managing team and developing Reports, Enhancement, User-exits, BADIs, SmartForms, Adobe Forms, SAP Script, JavaScript. I have experience in Sales and Distribution (SD), Sales Order Management (SOM) and Finance (FI) module, GTS, EHSM, PLM and GRC. I Have also worked on ABAP on HANA with CDS views.

Experience



Senior Consultant

Capgemini Technology Services India Ltd

Mar 2024 - Present (5 Months)

- Mentor and manage a small pod of developers.
- Assign tasks and projects based on skills and project needs for a major automotive manufacturer in Europe.
- Oversee resolution of incidents and service requests for MM, FI, SD, and PI modules.
- Prioritize and delegate incidents and tasks to ensure timely resolution.
- Track progress and ensure incidents and tasks meet SLA requirements.
- Handle Change and Transport System (ChaRM) requests for related SAP modules.
- Design and develop custom ABAP programs, reports, interfaces, enhancements, and forms (RICEF).
- Review and approve technical specifications and code from team members.
- Provide troubleshooting and support for integration issues.
- Plan and manage SAP development projects, including scoping, scheduling, and resource allocation.



System Development Engineer

Koch Business Solutions India

Apr 2022 - Mar 2024 (2 year)

- Enhanced custom reports and standard logic across various modules for more than 20+ Reports, FMs and Global Classes.
- Achieved up to 90% faster loading times for optimized custom reports, reducing delays in daily background jobs.
- Ensured compliance and user authorization by working on the GRC module.
- Managed Engineering Records and DMS for efficient product change notifications and MPS-related changes.
- Enhanced the existing SAP Business Client Application for processing Engineering Record to withdraw changes from certain changes which allowed the Engineering Department to reuse existing Engineering Records.
- Developed a RF program for Labeling Team which enabled the plant users to fasten the process by 70%.
- Resolved a critical issue causing an Engineering Records (ER) status blockage, preventing manufacturing delays by developing a program to reprocess the records in background where more than 164 records where stuck in production was processed.
- Successfully fixed a production issue related to the transfer of company data from SAP to the learning

website, which was critical for all users to be trained and be 100% compliant with Organization's Compliance policy for which was recognized by the management.

- Resolved a long pending issue in EHS where a report submits substance test report for all materials which was causing additional expense for the company.
- Currently Upskilling to SAP Ui5 and OData process along with BTP application development.

Senior Software Engineer at Accenture

Accenture

Oct 2021 - Apr 2022 (7 months)

- Developed more than 30 object modules for client who is a top pharmaceutical company in fortune 500.
- Resolved around 50+ Bug Tickets and around 10 Emergency Requests
- Developed modules in Sales & Distribution, Sales Order Management, Procurement and Finance Sectors.
- Developed several objects for Market's legal requirements for countries like Argentina, Portugal, India, and Turkey for Billing Invoice.
- Working in the Sales Order Management Offshore Development team developing reports, adobe form and Smartforms requirements.
- Developed programs for GTS related requirements to improve and optimize the response of the processing by 80% by revamping the old program.
- Worked on HANA Migration & Transformation project where I have developed several CDS views performance improvement and a Machine Learning project for defining and training the ML model of S/4HANA using the remote CDS View with Intelligent Scenario Lifecycle Management (ISLM).
- Conceptualized Interactive and Hierarchical Reports for analytical purposes which was sent as a mail for Business Leader's DL on time.

Software Engineer

Accenture

May 2020 - Oct 2021 (1 year 6 months)

Developed more than 10 object modules for client who is a top pharmaceutical company in fortune 500.

- Resolved around 50+ Bug Tickets and around 10 Emergency Requests
- Developed objects for modules in Sales & Distribution, Sales Order Management, Procurement and Finance Sectors.
- Identified and resolved performance bottlenecks in existing ABAP code. for more than 10 programs as a part of Performance Optimization Project(POP).
- Worked closely with cross-functional teams, including business analysts and project managers, to ensure alignment between technical solutions and business objectives.
- Acted as a mentor for junior developers for a team of 4 members, facilitating knowledge transfer and skill development within the team.

>

Associate Application Developer

Accenture in India

Apr 2018 - May 2020 (2 years 2 months)

- Developed more than 15 object modules for a Fortune 500 company.
- Have worked on more than 20 defects during the development of the project.
- Have created and maintained technical specification documents.
- Successfully reduced report execution times by 60% through code optimization, leading to improved operational efficiency.

Education



Sri Krishna College of Engineering and Technology

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Information Technology

Licenses & Certifications



EMC Academic Associate, Data Science and Big Data Analytics - EMC

SAP ABAP New Language Features - LearnABAP7.4&7.5 Syntax - Udemy Issued Aug 2023 - Expires Dec 2033

Skills

- SAP ABAP 7.4
- SAP Netweaver
- SAP PLM
- SAP Environment, Health, and Safety Management (EHS)
- SAP HANA
- RICEF
- · SAP Adobe Forms
- SAP Smart Forms
- SAPScript
- · SAP BusinessObjects
- SAP BTP RAP